# MADASIR MUHAMMAD ALI

GAME DEVELOPER

#### DETAILS

#### **ADDRESS**

Lahore Pakistan

#### PHONE

+92 3119831652

#### **EMAIL**

madasirali672@gmail.com

#### LINKS

Fiverr

GitHub (Personal)

GitHub (My Company)

#### SKILLS

Git

• • 0 0 0

C++

• • 0 0 0

Unity

. . . . .

C#

 $\bullet$   $\bullet$   $\circ$   $\circ$ 

X64 Assembly

• • • • •

## HOBBIES

Gaming / Playing, Thinking / Researching.

#### LANGUAGES

Urdu

. . . . .

Punjabi

English

 $\bullet$   $\bullet$   $\circ$   $\circ$ 

#### PROFILE

I am a programming <u>enthusiast</u>. Been programming from the **age of 12**. I like to view most of the possibilities to select a solution. With **4 + years Unity, C Sharp experience**. Learning graphics programming. And developing **new technologies** under my own studio <u>Plantae Games</u>. Passionate about parallel computing.

#### EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

## **Unity Developer, Data Games**

Lahore

Jun 2024 — Oct 2024

Working here on mobile games currently on **The Way of the Hunter** an open world animal hunting simulator game for mobile.

- · Developing systems to accelerate development.
- · Creating high quality Pre Rendered FHD Cinematics.
- · Integrating plugins to push development.
- · Writing large amount of high quality resuseable documented code.

## Programmer, NKX Studio

Remote

Jan 2023

Worked for a new Spanish startup <u>NKX Studio</u> as a **outsourced developer** with them. On an indie project **Aaron Crusade.** 

#### Freelancer, Fiverr

Remote

Jan 2022 — Dec 2022

Been freelanced for **2 years** on <u>Fiverr</u>. Worked in many projects having rating of **4.9**. Have been a **Level 1** seller.

- · 20+ Projects completed.
- Have done bug fixings for unity, python.
- Helped on outsourced projects.
- · Helped people to the right path.

## EDUCATION

## Matric, Preston international school

Lahore

Feb 2021 — Jul 2022

- 96.7% Marks.
- A+ Grade.

## Intermediate, Punjab College

Lahore

Oct 2022 — May 2024

#### Recent

Jan 2022 — Present

#### Job Projects:

#### · The Way of the Hunter:

- Apple AppStore Link
- An Open World, Animal Hunting, Simulator Mobile game. Where you are given hunting tasks to complete in the open world jungle.
- 110+ animals including birds at a time living in Open World Simulation. Some eating, resting, sleeping, roaming, in their habitable regions.
- High Quality Pre-Rendered FHD Cinematics. Lot more than a mobile game requires.
- · Task System for creating tasks.
- Tutorial System for creating tutorials.
- Extended UI Components of Unity.
- · Custom Save System for future cloud save compatibility.
- · Vehicle Controller, Jeeps to drive to habitat or to free roam.
- Different kind of weapons. i.e Snipers, ARs and others.
- · Different attachment for weapons. i.e Scopes, Magazines, Skins / Camos.

#### My Company Projects:

#### Fruit Hunter:

- · Google Play Store Link.
- Published my own Mobile Game, its 2D Pixel Art causal game. It was fun to develop during my intermediate board exams.
- It has Cloud Save, Leader-boards, Authentication, Analytics, iAP, ADmob Ads, Play Games.

#### Some Fiverr Projects:

### Live TikTok Interactive:

• The streamer can login to stream. Which shows the live messages on a corner on screen. And reactions on user interactions like with like a balloon with user profile image moves cross the screen. Like the streaming softwares that YouTubers use which shows their chat on screen but for TikTok. Along with the capability to be a game. Where users can take part i.e by sending a message.

### · Live interactive AI Show:

- · It was the Sponge Bob AI but with Team Fortress 2 characters.
- Characters move here and there, talk each other with chat got generated dialogs, get a text to speech for their respective character from another API then play a scenarios. It used chat gpt, fake you services.

## Personal Projects:

#### · Sharp Engine:

- A Game Engine in C# with editor in WPF framework D3D11 based.
- · Legacy Lighting, For Directional lights and Point Lights.
- · Shadow mapping for Directional Lights.
- Skybox Rendering.
- · Scriptable Pass based Render Pipeline.
- · Multiple and dockable window support for editor.
- · Editor components UI Serializer and custom editor scripting.
- OOPs Style Entity Component System or Unity Like.
- Forward Renderer.
- · (Development Declined)

#### · Live Wire! Remake:

- · Remake of the 1999 Play Station 1 Puzzle Game, Live Wire!
- From scratch in Cpp using Direct-X 11 for Windows.
- UI using IMGUI (Immediate GUI) library.
- PPM textures, STL models, Renderer done. Based on Baghdad Engine.
- · (Under Development.)
- · Baghdad Engine / Constantinople Engine:

- · Retry of making the Foundation of Technology that Muslim World is missing.
- · Cpp, D3D11, ImGUI, windows exclusive.
- · Currently giving base to Live Wire! Remake.

#### Idle Framework:

 A base for creating idle mobile games. Providing a fast start for the development by providing base for synchronization of actions by forcing state machine pattern. And providing utilities for clean execution of actions. (Partial of it is closed source under my company)

#### · X64 ASM Cube:

 A rotating ASCII cube made in x64 assembly language, showcasing my deep knowledge and understanding for the internal workings and execution of code.

#### · Grain Engine:

- Entity Component System is OOPs Style. Working under custom garbage collector.
- ECS, input system, basic renderer.
- · (Development declined)